Finding Aid for the Ruth St. Denis Papers LSC.1031
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 5: Media, 1900s-1960s
  - Subseries 5.2: Negatives, 1900s-1960s
    - Glass negatives
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Kwan Yin", undated (Box 177, Folder 49)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Kwan Yin", undated (Box 177, Folder 50)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Kwan Yin", undated (Box 177, Folder 51)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Kwan Yin", undated (Box 177, Folder 52)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Kwan Yin", undated (Box 177, Folder 53)
      - Ruth St. Denis - study, Lyric, undated (Box 177, Folder 54)
      - Ruth St. Denis - study, Lyric, undated (Box 177, Folder 55)
      - Ruth St. Denis - study, Lyric, undated (Box 177, Folder 56)
      - Ruth St. Denis - study, Lyric, undated (Box 177, Folder 57)
      - Ruth St. Denis - study, Lyric, undated (Box 177, Folder 58)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, Lyric - Drape study, undated (Box 177, Folder 59)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, Lyric - Standing study (High key), undated (Box 177, Folder 60)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, Scarf (slide is cracked, DAMAGED), undated (Box 182)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, Lyric - Scarf study (High key), undated (Box 177, Folder 62)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, Lyric - Scarf study, undated (Box 177, Folder 63)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, Lyric - Scarf study, undated (Box 177, Folder 64)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, Lyric - Scarf study, undated (Box 177, Folder 65)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, Lyric - Scarf study, "Soaring Scarf", undated (Box 177, Folder 66)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, Lyric - Scarf study, undated (Box 177, Folder 67)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, Lyric - Scarf study, undated (Box 177, Folder 68)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, Lyric - Scarf study, undated (Box 177, Folder 69)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, Lyric study, undated (Box 177, Folder 70)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, Head study - white hair Madonna, undated (Box 177, Folder 71)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Madonna", undated (Box 177, Folder 72)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Madrassi Nautch", undated (Box 177, Folder 73)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Miriam", undated (Box 177, Folder 74)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Nautch" head study, undated (Box 177, Folder 75)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Omika" (5 negatives), undated (Box 177, Folder 76)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, Oriental study, San Diego - Balboa Park - Doorway, undated (Box 177, Folder 77)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Oriental study," San Diego - Balboa Park, undated (Box 177, Folder 78)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo head study, North African, Ouled Nail, undated (Box 177, Folder 79)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo studies, "Ouled Nail," North African, undated (Box 177, Folder 80)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Ouled Nail," North African, undated (Box 177, Folder 81)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Ouled Nail," North African, undated (Box 177, Folder 82)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Ouled Nail," North African, undated (Box 177, Folder 83)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Peacock", undated (Box 177, Folder 84)
      - Ruth St. Denis - portrait with fan, undated (Box 177, Folder 85)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Red and Gold Sari", undated (Box 177, Folder 86)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Red and Gold Sari", undated (Box 177, Folder 87)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Sari," Studio 160 E 48th St., NY, undated (Box 177, Folder 88)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Sari" (8 negatives), undated (Box 177, Folder 89)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Sari," Studio 160 E 48th St., NY, undated (Box 177, Folder 90)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, Siamese Dance, undated (Box 177, Folder 91)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Ted Shawn, "Songs of Solomon", undated (Box 177, Folder 92)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Songs of Solomon", undated (Box 177, Folder 93)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Ted Shawn, "Songs of Solomon", undated (Box 177, Folder 94)
      - Ruth St. Denis, Ted Shawn and Denishawn Dancer, "Songs of Solomon", undated (Box 177, Folder 95)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Ted Shawn, "Songs of Solomon", undated (Box 177, Folder 96)
      - Ruth St. Denis, Ted Shawn and a Denishawn Dancer, "Songs of Solomon", undated (Box 177, Folder 97)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Ted Shawn, "Songs of Solomon", undated (Box 177, Folder 98)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Ted Shawn, "Songs of Solomon", undated (Box 177, Folder 99)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Ted Shawn, "Songs of Solomon", undated (Box 177, Folder 100)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Ted Shawn in "The Vision of the Oissoua," North African Ballet (Caution: slide is delicate), undated (Box 177, Folder 101)
      - Ruth St. Denis - study, undated (Box 177, Folder 102)
      - Ruth St. Denis - studio study (in pink dress), undated (Box 177, Folder 103)
      - Ruth St. Denis - studio study, undated (Box 177, Folder 104)
      - Ruth St. Denis - studio study, undated (Box 177, Folder 105)
      - Ruth St. Denis - standing study (high key) (DAMAGED: slide is cracked), undated (Box 182)
      - Ruth St. Denis - in studio - bending over flowers against window, undated (Box 177, Folder 107)
      - Ruth St. Denis - head study, undated (Box 177, Folder 108)
      - Ruth St. Denis - head study, undated (Box 177, Folder 109)
      - Ruth St. Denis - head study, Balboa, undated (Box 177, Folder 110)
      - Ruth St. Denis - head study, undated (Box 177, Folder 111)
      - Ruth St. Denis - head study, undated (Box 177, Folder 112)
      - Ruth St. Denis - 1924 head study (Box 177, Folder 113)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, head study, San Diego - Balboa Park, undated (Box 177, Folder 114)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Balboa, in doorway, undated (Box 177, Folder 115)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, study - in doorway, San Diego - Balboa Park, undated (Box 177, Folder 116)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, study at Lotus Pool, San Diego - Balboa Park, undated (Box 177, Folder 117)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, study (hat), San Diego - Balboa Park, undated (Box 177, Folder 118)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, head study - white hair, 1924 (Box 177, Folder 119)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, study - on couch, undated (Box 177, Folder 120)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, study on couch, undated (Box 177, Folder 121)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, head study in Sari, undated (Box 177, Folder 122)
      - Ruth St. Denis - head study, from the "Vision of the Cussoua," North African, undated (Box 177, Folder 123)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, head study in Sari costume, undated (Box 177, Folder 124)
      - Ruth St. Denis - study from "Vision of the Cussoua," North African Ballet, undated (Box 177, Folder 125)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo - from the "Vision of the Cussoua," North African (DAMAGED: slightly damaged slide), undated (Box 182)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo - "Vision of the Cussoua," North African Ballet, undated (Box 177, Folder 127)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn and Co., "The Vision of the Cussoua," North African Ballet, undated (Box 177, Folder 128)
      - Ruth St. Denis - scene from "Coffee House," N. African, "The Vision of the Cussoua," "Ouled Nail", undated (Box 177, Folder 129)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Daucus - "Coffee House," "Vision of the Cussoua," "Ouled Nail," North African, undated (Box 177, Folder 130)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Daucus in scene from "Coffee House," "Vision of the Cussoua," "Ouled Nail," North African, undated (Box 177, Folder 131)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Daucus in scene from "Coffee House," "Vision of the Cussoua," "Ouled Nail," North African, undated (Box 177, Folder 132)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Cobra", undated (Box 178, Folder 1)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Cobra", undated (Box 178, Folder 2)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Cobra", undated (Box 178, Folder 3)
      - Ruth St. Denis - "Daughter of the Shiek," Mitchell Garden, undated (Box 178, Folder 4)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Eagle Rock, Denishawn Dancers (The beginning of Soaring), undated (Box 178, Folder 5)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, 10 negatives, Denishawn Dancers on hilltop at Eagle Rock, undated (Box 178, Folder 6)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers (Trio), undated (Box 178, Folder 7)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Eagle Rock, Denishawn Dancers (around pepper tree), undated (Box 178, Folder 8)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Ted Shawn with dancers, 5 negatives, undated (Box 178, Folder 9)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, Ruth Austin, Doris Humphrey, Claire Niles (with musical instruments), undated (Box 178, Folder 10)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancer (Anna Austin in "Lyric Study"), undated (Box 178, Folder 11)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Eagle Rock, Denishawn Dancers, undated (Box 178, Folder 12)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers (Katherine Hawley in tree), undated (Box 178, Folder 13)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers (cracked pot), undated (Box 178, Folder 14)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancer, "study", undated (Box 178, Folder 15)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancer, figurine with water jug, undated (Box 178, Folder 16)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, undated (Box 178, Folder 17)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers (Everett and Girls), undated (Box 178, Folder 18)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, "Trio", undated (Box 178, Folder 19)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Denishawn Dancers - Eagle Rock, undated (Box 178, Folder 20)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancer (Betty May), undated (Box 178, Folder 21)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers (Trio), (DAMAGED: plate cracked and broken, piece missing), undated (Box 182)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancer, study (Isidora Duncan), undated (Box 178, Folder 23)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers at Balboa Park - San Diego, undated (Box 178, Folder 24)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers at Balboa Park - San Diego, undated (Box 178, Folder 25)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers at Balboa Park - San Diego, undated (Box 178, Folder 26)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, by the Lotus Pond, undated (Box 178, Folder 27)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, dancing in the courtyard, undated (Box 178, Folder 28)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, with 2 dancers, undated (Box 178, Folder 29)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, with dancers (DAMAGED: cracked plate), undated (Box 182)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, study by a pool, undated (Box 178, Folder 31)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, undated (Box 178, Folder 32)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, undated (Box 178, Folder 33)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, undated (Box 178, Folder 34)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, undated (Box 178, Folder 35)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, Katherine and girls, undated (Box 178, Folder 36)
      - Ruth St. Denis - East Indian study, Mitchell Garden, undated (Box 178, Folder 37)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, East Indian, undated (Box 178, Folder 38)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, East Indian, undated (Box 178, Folder 39)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "East Indian with dancers", undated (Box 178, Folder 40)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, "Egyptian Figures", undated (Box 178, Folder 41)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, "Egypta", undated (Box 178, Folder 42)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, "The Elopement," Mitchell Garden, undated (Box 178, Folder 43)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona - "The Gift of Eternal Life", undated (Box 178, Folder 44)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "The Gift of Eternal Life", undated (Box 178, Folder 45)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, 6 negatives, "The Gift of Eternal Life", undated (Box 178, Folder 46)
      - Ruth St. Denis - "Greek," Mitchell Garden, undated (Box 178, Folder 47)
      - Ruth St. Denis - "Greek," Mitchell Garden, undated (Box 178, Folder 48)
      - Ruth St. Denis - "Greek," Mitchell Garden, undated (Box 178, Folder 49)
      - Ruth St. Denis - "Greek," Mitchell Garden, undated (Box 178, Folder 50)
      - Ruth St. Denis - "Greek," Mitchell Garden, undated (Box 178, Folder 51)
      - Ruth St. Denis - "Greek," Mitchell Garden, undated (Box 178, Folder 52)
      - Ruth St. Denis - "Greek," Mitchell Garden, Ruth St. Denis and Bess Becker, undated (Box 178, Folder 53)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Greek study, Anthony Garden, undated (Box 178, Folder 54)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Craig W and Greek, Krotona, undated (Box 178, Folder 55)
      - Ruth St. Denis - San Diego, Denishawn Dancers, Greek Trio, undated (Box 178, Folder 56)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancer, Doris Humphrey in "Hoop Dance", undated (Box 178, Folder 57)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, "Lotus Pool", undated (Box 178, Folder 58)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Lotus Pond", undated (Box 178, Folder 59)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, Oriental Trio, undated (Box 178, Folder 60)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Oriental Study", undated (Box 178, Folder 61)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Oriental Study", undated (Box 178, Folder 62)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, Oriental Study by Pool, undated (Box 178, Folder 63)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Oriental Study at Fountain", undated (Box 178, Folder 64)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Oriental Study with dancers", undated (Box 178, Folder 65)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Mitchell Garden, undated (Box 178, Folder 66)
      - Ted Shawn - Craig Ward, Mitchell Garden, undated (Box 178, Folder 67)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Mitchell Garden, undated (Box 178, Folder 68)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Mitchell Garden, undated (Box 178, Folder 69)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Mitchell Garden, undated (Box 178, Folder 70)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Mitchell Garden, undated (Box 178, Folder 71)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Mitchell Garden, undated (Box 178, Folder 72)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, "Music Visualization" around oak tree, undated (Box 178, Folder 73)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, "Music Visualization", undated (Box 178, Folder 74)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, "Music Visualization", undated (Box 178, Folder 75)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, "Music Visualization", undated (Box 178, Folder 76)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, "Music Visualization", undated (Box 178, Folder 77)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancer, "Music Visualization", undated (Box 178, Folder 78)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, "Music Visualization", undated (Box 178, Folder 79)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, "Music Visualization", undated (Box 178, Folder 80)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, "Music Visualization", undated (Box 178, Folder 81)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, "Music Visualization", undated (Box 178, Folder 82)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, "Music Visualization", undated (Box 178, Folder 83)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, "Music Visualization", undated (Box 178, Folder 84)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, "Music Visualization," San Diego, undated (Box 178, Folder 85)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, "Music Visualization", undated (Box 178, Folder 86)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, "Music Visualization" on hilltop in Eagle Rock, 6 negatives, undated (Box 178, Folder 87)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, "Music Visualization," 24 negatives, undated (Box 178, Folder 88)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Peacock", undated (Box 178, Folder 89)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Peacock", undated (Box 178, Folder 90)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Peacock", undated (Box 178, Folder 91)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Peacock", undated (Box 178, Folder 92)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Peacock", undated (Box 178, Folder 93)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Peacock", undated (Box 178, Folder 94)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Peacock", undated (Box 178, Folder 95)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Peacock", undated (Box 178, Folder 96)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Peacock", undated (Box 178, Folder 97)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Peacock", undated (Box 178, Folder 98)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Peacock", undated (Box 178, Folder 99)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, Greek "Sappho," Bess Becker- Aphrodite, undated (Box 178, Folder 100)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Craig Ward at Krotona, "Sappho and Phaon", undated (Box 178, Folder 101)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Sappho and Phaon," 2 negatives, undated (Box 178, Folder 102)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Bess Becker, Krotona, "Sappho", undated (Box 178, Folder 103)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Bess Becker, Krotona, "Sappho", undated (Box 178, Folder 104)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Craig Ward, Krotona, "Sappho", undated (Box 178, Folder 105)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Craig Ward, Krotona, "Sappho", undated (Box 178, Folder 106)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Craig Ward, Krotona, "Sappho and Phaon", undated (Box 178, Folder 107)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Craig Ward, Krotona, "Sappho and Phaon", undated (Box 178, Folder 108)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Craig Ward, Krotona, "Sappho", undated (Box 178, Folder 109)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Craig Ward, Krotona, "Sappho and Phaon", undated (Box 178, Folder 110)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Craig Ward at Krotona, "Sappho and Phaon", undated (Box 178, Folder 111)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Craig Ward at Krotona, "Sappho and Phaon", undated (Box 178, Folder 112)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Sappho", undated (Box 178, Folder 113)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Craig Ward, Krotona, "Sappho and Phaon", undated (Box 178, Folder 114)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Sari", undated (Box 178, Folder 115)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Sari", undated (Box 178, Folder 116)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, seated, wearing Sari (DAMAGED: plate damaged), undated (Box 182)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, wearing "Sari", undated (Box 178, Folder 118)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Sari", undated (Box 178, Folder 119)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancer, "Scarf Dance", undated (Box 178, Folder 120)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, "Sonata Pathetique", undated (Box 178, Folder 121)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, "Sonata Pathetique", undated (Box 178, Folder 122)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, "Sonata Pathetique", undated (Box 178, Folder 123)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, "Synchoric", undated (Box 178, Folder 124)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, "Synchoric" (negative), undated (Box 178, Folder 125)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers, "Synchoric", undated (Box 178, Folder 126)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancer at "Tedruth" posed by tree, undated (Box 178, Folder 127)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers at "Tedruth" in Eagle Rock, California, undated (Box 178, Folder 128)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, Denishawn Dancers at "Tedruth", undated (Box 178, Folder 129)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Theodora", undated (Box 178, Folder 130)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Theodora", undated (Box 178, Folder 131)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Theodora", undated (Box 178, Folder 132)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Ted Shawn, "The Tryst," Mitchell Garden, undated (Box 178, Folder 133)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Krotona, "Water Carrier", undated (Box 178, Folder 134)
      - Ruth St. Denis - "The Water Carrier," Mitchell Garden, undated (Box 178, Folder 135)
      - Ruth St. Denis at Yosemite, undated (Box 179, Folder 1)
      - Ruth St. Denis study, reclining figure, undated (Box 179, Folder 2)
      - Ruth St. Denis- study, "White Hair", 1924 (Box 179, Folder 3)
      - Ruth St. Denis- Study of..., undated (Box 179, Folder 4)
      - Ruth St. Denis- Study of..., undated (Box 179, Folder 5)
      - Ruth St. Denis- studio study (DAMAGED: corner broken off of glass plate), undated (Box 182)
      - Ruth St. Denis- Study of..., undated (Box 179, Folder 7)
      - Ruth St. Denis- study for a mural, undated (Box 179, Folder 8)
      - Ruth St. Denis- study for a mural, undated (Box 179, Folder 9)
      - Ruth St. Denis- study for a mural, undated (Box 179, Folder 10)
      - Ruth St. Denis- 2 negatives, "Personal" - San Diego?, 1 solo, 1 with friend - unidentified, undated (Box 179, Folder 11)
      - Ruth St. Denis- solo (in Sari at piano), undated (Box 179, Folder 12)
      - Ruth St. Denis at Ampico piano, undated (Box 179, Folder 13)
      - Ruth St. Denis at piano, undated (Box 179, Folder 14)
      - Ruth St. Denis at piano, undated (Box 179, Folder 15)
      - Ruth St. Denis at Ampico piano, undated (Box 179, Folder 16)
      - Ruth St. Denis at Ampico piano, undated (Box 179, Folder 17)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, with scarf, undated (Box 179, Folder 18)
      - Ruth St. Denis - "Greek Veil", undated (Box 179, Folder 19)
      - Ruth St. Denis - "Cobra", undated (Box 179, Folder 20)
      - Ruth St. Denis - "Greek Study", undated (Box 179, Folder 21)
      - Ruth St. Denis and Ted Shawn - Eagle Rock, "Into the Promised Land", undated (Box 179, Folder 22)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Eagle Rock, 3 negatives, nude studios, undated (Box 179, Folder 23)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Eagle Rock at Tedruth, undated (Box 179, Folder 24)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Eagle Rock, East Indian, undated (Box 179, Folder 25)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Eagle Rock, "nude study", undated (Box 179, Folder 26)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Eagle Rock, "nude study", undated (Box 179, Folder 27)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Eagle Rock, "nude study", undated (Box 179, Folder 28)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Eagle Rock, "nude study", undated (Box 179, Folder 29)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Eagle Rock, "nude study", undated (Box 179, Folder 30)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Eagle Rock, "nude study", undated (Box 179, Folder 31)
      - Ruth St. Denis - "Ahasuerus", undated (Box 179, Folder 32)
      - Ruth St. Denis - "Ahasuerus", undated (Box 179, Folder 33)
      - Ruth St. Denis - "Ahasuerus", undated (Box 179, Folder 34)
      - Ruth St. Denis - "Lotus Pool," Ahasuerus, undated (Box 179, Folder 35)
      - Ruth St. Denis - 23 musical negatives, undated (Box 179, Folder 36)
      - Ruth St. Denis - 23 musical negatives, undated (Box 179, Folder 37)
      - Ruth St. Denis - Topanga?, 14 negatives, undated (Box 179, Folder 38)
      - Ruth St. Denis - 10 negatives, 1931 December (Box 179, Folder 39)
      - Ted Shawn - 2 negatives, undated (Box 179, Folder 40)
      - Ted Shawn - 2 negatives, teaching, undated (Box 179, Folder 41)
      - Ted Shawn - London, 4 negatives, undated (Box 179, Folder 42)
      - Ruth St. Denis - 5 negatives, Ted Shawn, undated (Box 179, Folder 43)
      - Ruth St. Denis - 40 musical negatives, undated (Box 179, Folder 44)
      - Ted Shawn - proofs, undated (Box 179, Folder 45)
      - Glass negatives: DAMAGED, undated (Box 182)
  - Subseries 5.3: Reel to reel tapes
    The reel-to-reel tapes are recordings of St. Denis reading her autobiography.
    Restrictions on Access
    Audio reel to reels must be digitized prior to use.
    - "An Unfinished Life" part 1, undated (Box 156, Folder 1)
    - "An Unfinished Life" part 2, undated (Box 156, Folder 2)